Guide to the Minnie Fisher Cunningham Papers 2006-010
University of Houston Libraries Special Collections
- Texas Equal Suffrage Association (TESA) Activity, 1915-1920
  - Organizational Materials, undated
    - Texas Railroads Map, Removed from Box 3 Folder 32: Outline for County Campaign; Lists of County Chairmen; Suffrage Associations by Counties; Record of County Population; Map, undated (Drawer F.3, Ovs folder 8)
  - Speakers and Organizers, 1917-1919
    - Correspondence with Marie B. Ames, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with Edna H. Beveridge, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Frances E. Brewer, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with Lavinia Engle, 1917-1918 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with Augusta Hughston, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with Mona S. McMahon, Alma Sasse, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Lola Trax, Gertrude Watkins, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Speaker's Bureau, 1917-1919
    - Correspondence, A-B, Reports, April 7-May 23 1919 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, C, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, D-G, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence H-K, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence L-M, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence N-P, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence R-T, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence W, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence with legislators, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Form letters, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence and lecture information, 1917-1919 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Expense accounts - Ames, Beveridge, Brewer, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Expense accounts - Cunningham, Hughston, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Expense accounts - Sasse, Tips, Trax, others, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Clippings, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - List of county chairmen, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Political Activities, 1914-1919
  - Political correspondence, 1916-1919
    - Jess Baker; Carlos Bee, 1916-1918 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Eugene Black, Thomas Blanton, 1916-1919 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - W. J. Bryan; J. P. Buchanan, 1917-1919 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - B, 1916-1919 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - M. M. Crane; Tom Connally; C. A. Culberson, 1917-1919 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Henry Clark; C; D, 1917-1919 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Joe Eagle, 1917-1919 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - J. A. Elkins, 1918-1919 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - F; G, 1917-1919 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - W. L. Hill; W. C. Hogg; H, 1917-1919 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Marvin Jones; Thomas King, 1917-1919 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - L, 1917-1918 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - C. B. Metcalfe; J. C. McNealus, 1917-1919 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Jeff McLemore; M; P, 1917-1919 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Morris Sheppard, 1917-1919 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Ocie Speer; Hatton V. Summer, 1917-1919 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - S, 1917-1919 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - T; U, 1917-1919 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - W, 1917-1919 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Y, 1917-1919 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Legislative replies to Jane McCallum's request for support for suffrage, January 1918 - January 1919 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Political contests, 1914-1919
    - Childers - Chambliss, correspondence and campaign materials, October - November 1918 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Clay Stone Briggs - W. L. Hill, correspondence, campaign materials, August - November 1918 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Glasscock - Parr, correspondence, campaign materials, October 1918 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Annie Webb Blanton - correspondence, 1917-1919 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Annie Webb Blanton - correspondence, reports, materials relating to campaign for State Superintendent of Public Instruction, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - James Ferguson - correspondence and materials relating to, 1917-1918 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - James Ferguson - clippings, undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - William P. Hobby - campaign correspondence, April - August 1918 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - William P. Hobby - general correspondence, 1914-1919 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - William P. Hobby - Galveston campaign materials, minutes of campaign committee meetings, undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - William P. Hobby - campaign petitions, undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - William P. Hobby - miscellaneous campaign material, lists of Ferguson supporters, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - William P. Hobby - publicity materials, undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - William P. Hobby - clippings, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Correspondence - various candidates, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Reports on candidates, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Publicity materials - various candidates, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Clippings - various candidates, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Political Lists, 1917; undated
    - Texas legislators - voting records, etc; County chairmen - various campaigns, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Congressional Districts; Congressional Districts, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - U.S. Congressional suffrage vote; miscellaneous lists, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Anti-Vice Reported Activity, 1917-1919
  - Constitution, reports, outlines - Texas Social Hygiene Association, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - General correspondence, Texas Congress of Mothers, 1917-1918 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Circular letters, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Financial statements, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Lists, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Reports, resolutions, outlines, minutes, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Laws, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Photographs - saloons, San Antonio "inspection" house, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Pamphlets, literature, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Pamphlets, literature, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 6, Folder 29-31)
  - WCTU - correspondence with Nannie W. Curtis; Anti-Saloon League - correspondence, 1917-1919 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Prohibition materials, undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Prohibition clippings, undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Child Welfare - General correspondence, 1918-1919 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Child Welfare - Circular letters - Council of National Defense and Dept. of Labor, undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Child Welfare - Materials and literature, undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Labor - General correspondence with Women's Trade Union League and other labor organizations, 1917-1919 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Labor - Press releases - National Women's Trade Union League, undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Labor - Press releases - U.S. Dept. of Labor; National Federation of Federal Employees, undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence - Prison reform; education; Texas Women Bankers Assn, undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence, 1917-1919
    - Outlines and reports - Brownsville and Texas border, Dallas, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Lists and reports - Ft. Worth, Galveston, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Reports - Houston, San Antonio, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Lists of prostitutes and panderers, reports - Waco, other towns, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - A-C, 1917-1918 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - D-G, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - H-L, 1917-1918 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - M-P, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - R-T, 1917-1918 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Elizabeth Speer, 1917-1918 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - War Department, 1916-1918 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - V-Z and anonymous letters, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Mary D. Woodson, 1915-1918 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Chicago Law and Order League; Council of Jewish Women, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Texas Social Hygiene Association, 1917-1919 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- War Effort Activities, 1917-1918
  - National Surgical Dressings Committee, correspondence; War Work Council, 1918 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Food Conservation - general correspondence and correspondence with Mary E. Gearing, State Organizer, 1917-1918 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Food Conservation - organization outline and literature, undated (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Thrift Committee - miscellaneous materials, undated (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Conservation and Thrift - clippings, undated (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Council of National Defense - correspondence and miscellaneous materials, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Council of National Defense - Newsletters, Women's Committee, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - War Savings Committee - correspondence, 1917-1918 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - War Saving Committee - materials, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Women's Overseas Hospital Unit - correspondence and other material, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Americanization materials, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous materials, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Clippings; copy of Reconnaissance, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Liberty Loan, undated
    - General correspondence, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Circular letters, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - General correspondence, 1918 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Circular letters, 1918 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Financial records, undated (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Organizational materials, undated (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - General correspondence, mundated correspondence, miscellaneous notes, 1918-1919 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Literature, undated (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - State reports, undated (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Index, undated (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Clippings, undated (Box 6, Folder 52)
- Democratic Party Activities, 1916-1920
  - Woodrow Wilson - correspondence, 1918-1919 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Woodrow Wilson - clippings, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous materials, 1916-1918 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Texas Woman's Democratic League - correspondence, 1918-1919 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Gubernatorial Candidates - correspondence, materials, concerning Pat Neff, 1919-1920 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Pat Neff, clippings, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Gubernatorial Candidates - R. E. Thomason, correspondence with MFC, 1917-1920 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Thomason for Governor - correspondence, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 16-17)
  - Thomason for Governor - correspondence concerning campaign organization, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Thomason for Governor - clippings and handouts, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Democratic National Convention correspondence, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Democratic National Convention campaign literature, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Democratic National Convention campaign literature and speeches, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Miscellaneous Activities, 1915-1920
  - Correspondence: Women's organizations; Texas Federation of Women's Clubs, 1917-1919 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Women's organizations; Texas Federation of Women's Clubs, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence - University matters, 1917 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Clippings - University matters, 1917 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence - Cato Sells, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence - League of Women Voters, undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - League of Women Voters, undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence - Cunningham, undated (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Labor, undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Suffrage - plays, speeches, etc, undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Suffrage - issues of Woman Citizen, Maryland Suffrage News, undated (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Political - issues of Bob Schuler's Free Lance concerning Ferguson, Hobby or suffrage, undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Suffrage - clippings and news releases, state and party campaigns, undated (Box 7, Folder 36-39)
  - Suffrage - Legislative petitions, Galveston, Dallas counties, undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Suffrage - Legislative petitions, Bexar, Anderson counties, undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - American Red Cross, Block organization, League to Enforce Peace, Military Welfare Commission, etc, undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 8, Folder 1-8)
  - Political materials - Suffrage endorsements; campaign instructions; Legislative bills; Resolutions, 1917-1919 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Suffrage handouts and literature, 1915-1918 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Suffrage materials, 1917-1918 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Suffrage poems and songs, 1917 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Suffrage correspondence, 1916-1919 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Clippings, undated (Drawer F.9, Ovs folder 9)
- Later Years, 1920-1964
  - Agricultural Adjustment Agency, 1940-1943 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1938-1960 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Crossing Over, 1935-1960 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Crossing Over, undated (Box 8, Folder 17-18)
  - Democratic Party, 1944-1961 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Gubernatorial Campaign, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous, 1937-1962 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Newspaper Clippings about MFC, 1927-1964 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Photographs MFC, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Photographs (others), 1961 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Political Organizations, 1922-1946 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Speeches and Notes, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Tributes, 1920-1964 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Texas Democratic Women's State Committee, 1954-1959 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook: M. F. Cunningham's gubernatorial campaign, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Photograph - MFC, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Photograph - MFC, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 3)